welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
oh alright look at the Stoa I'm Peter
stewardess Noah still has a place for us
to go here and dialogue about what
matters most at the nice edge and we got
the beautiful sexy and hot Akira the
dawn and then he's doing we're gonna do
a quick Q&A 30 minutes and then we're
gonna jump into another link we're gonna
put in the chat box and then we're gonna
have a livestream party with Akira so
that being said
Akira my good man yeah we had a full day
of Petersons fest here we had left us
coming in we had activists coming in we
just watched the film that the Verizon
store and Peterson did you enjoy it yeah
yeah I did it
I can't I can't hear because you keep
your voice keeps going in and out
turning it up how's that yeah that's
good
I bet had you seen it before no first
time what would be feeling it left you
with I missed them I was talking excuse
my therapist for two years I think I
told you that
and then so um I just like far where's
Peterson like I want to back yeah yeah
and I think I saw a couple tweets so
you're saying that too
oh I mean I'm seeing that all over the
place obviously obviously you know I'm
kind of I have a lot of love in my
audience and connected to me and what
have you so I see that every day every
day I see that but I find him interest
with the film because I saw the film
like before the departure or before the
the awareness of the departure that
makes sense and I was with monitoring
people's reactions to it and depending
on like your viewpoint you people were
getting completely different vibes in
the film some people it's scared like
some people were quite terrified at the
end some people have got this kind of
like like dark thing from it it was
really I think it was very kind of well
made in that it didn't present itself in
any fashion
other than being a document and
essentially you see in it what you're
used to the reflection as in you see
your own biases or what have you coming
through and you get and you can kind of
it was impartial I fell yeah yeah yeah
if you go if you search reactions around
Twitter some people were terrified by it
some people saw a very clear document of
a deliberate like Messiah type thing
being Bill deliberately they wanted to
see out of that documentary yeah yeah
and what did you get out of it I felt
like it was the first part of a
beautiful trilogy oh you know we talked
about this stuff you know and
everything's in stories and it makes
completely sense that you boy piece and
would have his whole life become a sort
of archetypal story it was like the
first Star Wars maybe right yeah and you
got you basically launched a mini wave
thing with Peterson so the first song I
did that you would call me wave I did
low as a proto meaning wave like my
whole life I made songs that sampled
people talking but the first song he
would go meaning wave was indeed a song
the sample Jordan Peterson talking about
the importance of being a really good
plumber you you know which really struck
me at 4:00 in the morning half-baked
coming back from DJing in West Hollywood
nor denied installation on YouTube on a
projector and a Jordan B isn't lecture
being on and you certainly starts
talking about you know be a plumber be a
good one and it really hit me that
really hit me I was like damn I need to
sample this right now that's just epic
be a plumber be a good work because if
you had to notice something about him
talking about the importance of just
like you know just doing an honest thing
I mean the power of that in the world it
seems like in it seems like an odd thing
that would be the thing that would
really spark complete inspiration but it
did three things out that week and one
of them was there and one of them was
attract that sampled grand theft auto
san andreas all you had to do was follow
the damn train CJ some people mean you
know
and another song about the Welsh notion
of Hittites which is a nostalgic for a
place that doesn't exist anymore
and uh three songs and uh that one was
the one that reading resonated yeah
began that Jimmy so I have two questions
and I have a strategy I want to share
with you if everyone has any questions
just write in the chat box or any
statements and then I'll calling you and
meet yourself so the first question then
I'll make I'll share the strategy is so
we're talking okay so I mention this in
the last session that so I thought
Peterson that client for two years and
the last my last session with him was
when he released a pronoun video
actually just worked out like that and
then he's just famous but just before I
saw him I started to see him as a client
so basically two years before he came
famous I was saying to buddy of mine
like how come this guy is not more
famous right now is he in toronto he's
like an indie band like you know people
kind of knew him but he wasn't that that
popular then now I was like how's this
guy this fucking famous it's just like
yeah he says he's he says things that
are good but it's like it's not like big
like groundbreaking in a way but it's
like there's like a combination of
things about him that makes him special
so I'm curious what your thoughts have
been why Peterson was the guy that had
such a force in this culture and had
such controversy and polarization around
him well it's the thing I always say and
people people forget certain people
having these sorts of comforts that
conversations forget that it's pointless
to preach to the choir you want to reach
the normies and you want to reach people
outside the choir and a Peterson had a
way of communicating quite complex epic
ideas to regular people in a way that
they could understand and in a way that
they felt was genuine he's not talking
down to you he's not talking in a way
that's overtly unnecessarily complicated
he has a way of boiling down quite big
ideas into concepts that you can grip if
you're RIT like a regular person
you know so he had that going for it and
then on the other side he had this
wonderful knack of getting
in some kind of an epic drama every week
you know which that's the milkshake that
brings all the boys to be yard you know
is that drama so you being a new beef
every week and he be getting he got a
new supervillain enemy to fight every
week so you know that became exciting
and then people would go and so some
people would tune in for the drama but
then they would stay for the epic back
catalog of bangers there was his YouTube
channel there was stuffed full of
lectures of just breaking down the Bible
in terms that atheists could understand
like he reintroduced Western culture to
generations of people who didn't know
nothing about it
which is why I can compare him with
what's because walleston what's
introduced Eastern culture to people who
didn't know nothing about it and then
you had two generations of Western
people who didn't really have Western
culture explain to them in a way other
than it's bad okay you know and he came
in and he's like in the similar way say
like Joseph Campbell came in and
translated things he translated old
things in a way that made sense now
and Petersen did something similar but
he had the anat added bonus of all that
drama he did the 50s damn thing I've
said this before
he used exactly the same playbook than
50 cent did and 6-9 more recently and
they could continue something we talked
about a previous conversation we had
like so when I was as a client used to
go to his office and he had all this
books and then a bookshelf to the right
had this whole section on hell on serial
killers evil all this time is that he's
like whoa
and and when I sort of like I was
talking to you like I'm following this
energy I'm calling the Dame on and then
like the Dame on sort of leads you to
like demonic energies and you actually
feel like when you're following that
it's like sounds a woo to some people
but it's like this primordial language
that you're speaking and Peterson speaks
that language I feel it's like you feel
his fucking words we're all these sort
of like disembodied intellectuals
they're just talking from like a
monotone
space and I feel you're plugged into
that primordial language as well or you
can write
Segan it's the conduit saying yes like
you because if you if you if you get
into that zone if you get particular
good enough a thing and if u fokin a
focus off focus enough on that thing and
doing that thing you know what do you
spend forty years thinking about the
same fuckin thing
in incredibly obsessive detail and
reading everything about it I've spent
decades on this music thing the similar
way if you just keep doing that you
become a conduit for something alan
moore used to call it idea space or
whatever grande Morrison calls it a
fifth dimension whatever like you become
a conduit so that whatever that is and
if you are pure in your intention of
where have you that just comes through
and people fucking recognize that and
it's undeniable it's also something that
can't be copied yes that's what happened
with the IDW things lots of people try
to like get them get that but they
couldn't because they were not fucking
conduits in that fashion for whatever
reason it's like not a thing it's not a
thing you can copy and it's not a thing
you can do over the course of a weekend
yeah that way and some people study and
some people have an accident it's like
what any kind of superpower you know
someone falls into a very vast it you
know somebody builds a fucking machine
and spends a long time doing it someone
has some cosmic rays or whatever the
fuck it is or someone's born a mutant so
here's the strategy I agree with that by
the way but here's the strategy
so Jordan Hall reached out to John
breaking and I and this is it was a lot
of synchronicity surrounding this and
the idea is to get Peterson into a
private conversation in dialog O's with
John and a few other people in the sense
making web before he enters into the
sort of the culture war or whatever if
we can kind of do that move in order to
push him at his edge of his thinking in
two phases
maybe postmodern shadows or whatever it
is and on a sense that I don't know if
you could help with that but anything
that resonates with you with that
strategy what has anyone spoken to him
there's anyone like Larry
yahuwah was his re-entry plan is there
anything like that people were where
where is that but they don't know where
does reentry plan is and i think we yeah
those it wasn't I mean if you want any
more specifics about topics or anything
of that nature or the way you would like
to do it or whatever forum or whatever
kind of thing it is I know he's already
homies with rocky anyway right yeah so
they have like a frenemy type
relationship there were like buddy he'd
they were like the two there's another
guide and older men they're like the
three life-changing professors at the
University of Toronto and then Vicki and
Peterson they had a lot of disagreements
but there was respect and then Peterson
just and then reveille he too started
coming on the scene recently in sort of
a kind of a sense making rebel wisdom
space with his meeting crisis series
that you've been listening to yeah there
was a crossover I saw uh that was a
thing they did together you see the
while ago yeah that's before he he
launched got launched onto the culture
war scene visit yeah that's great I
really enjoyed that
yeah and so good before I pivot to the
Q&A steel the culture think we can do it
it's got two or three choruses yeah it's
very big it's one of the abuse way it
happened for it came together very
quickly came together just so I wanted
to as well so yeah hopefully you like it
I have a good feeling I will yeah it's
great right I know it's good because I
keep waking up with it in my head and
then were the ones that that's the them
are the good ones
it's what people who don't know what
we're talking about so John verdict he
mentioned something at the store for
like the first week at the stores launch
you just small teeny says we gotta steal
the culture and I sent that to Akira and
he loved it and he's creating a song and
I'm just like oh yeah I think I'd like a
fanboy and I think
and actually Joe Joe you're the one that
asked that question of jonov a key that
inspired the question is dealing culture
and you're here do you wanna and you
have a statement er that's correct I
think I own that trademark thank you
very much you're in it you're I mean if
it was your voice there's a bit where
whoever asked him the question doesn't
response to him and that's in there it's
really jealous now Joe yeah yeah in
Knight the middle a bit just before the
guitar solo I mean yeah so
congratulations there was a good ask
question that did that because that what
that bought out was one of those what we
were just talking about that was a very
pure thing that was a pure impassioned
like real thing he came out of that
man's head that came out that man's face
hole the only that was powerful it is
interesting because the next day I asked
the same question in Jordan Hall and you
know like Jordan Holly gave a much more
strategic in general like answer um and
maybe there's something where those two
maybe there's something on Bonet ssin of
those two answers can lead to something
but John's answer is real good his Roman
yeah I have to hit this into Jordan
formerly green horse because I do like
that man he is an epic fellow and he's
come in tomorrow at 11 a.m. Eastern Time
at the store to do a situational
assessment on the riots so if you want
to come join us secure feel free I'm
streaming all day oh I wonder if I could
like pull it in and like DJ over the top
of it awesome you could be the opening
opening I figured Jacob
you had a question for Akira well
let's take it server that so you're just
going back to the thing you said about
conduits being conduit and then you said
conduits for whatever the hell it is so
my question is do you really not know
what the hell it is or are you just
glossing yeah I think you know I'm a
humble beet gardener you know and
there's also many ways of describing
this thing and as one of the things I've
been documenting in my humble beet
gardening is that there you know the
thing as many names and there are many
ways of describing it and picking one I
don't see the point you know so if I can
refer to in a way that you understand
what I'm talking about
and someone else does then then it
achieves his purpose so just one
follow-up question I don't think JP
would like that cuz he would say if you
want to bring it out of its blurry
background you got to name it but yeah
but like I said it's got lots of
different names there's many many
different names and many people call it
by different names am I supposed to list
them all it'd be like fucking Khaleesi
and Game of Thrones no definitely don't
list them all thank lip hey you're
welcome
excellent moustache okay Raj lol RJ Lee
oh I don't know right yet a question
about you yeah yeah I'm a big fan and I
was just always curious since you have
to spend a lot of time having the
repetition and these thoughts constantly
you know going off in your head as
you're editing them how much do they
affect you during like the creation and
editing process yeah completely I mean
they do completely you become possessed
by the things and that could be good and
that could be bad if you're doing a
record with David Goggins and he's
constantly talking about fuck your world
suddenly starts going to shit and you
start having accidents and you start
getting hit by fucking cars and falling
off your scooter and things fall on you
out of the fucking sky that album was a
fuck
nor do you know the the the one I did
recently the Alan was one was a joy
because you know he's talking about
duality perception is selection or
that's like the thing being able to
choose all that's and he's laughing a
lot it's very fun and playful and the
life was wonderful during the creation
of that record you know you got to be
careful with this shit but sometimes you
have to go into the dark places the
Joseph Campbell one was a split between
the two and so that had some some side
effects
you know Grant Morrison who is a comic
book writer and a friend of mine and
I've learnt a lot of his processes and
what-have-you from hanging out with him
and he wrote a comic book called the
Invisibles which was a cent which was a
deliberate hyper sigil designed to
change the world in which the lead
character was an insert of him and he
kept putting this character in
situations and those things would then
happen in his life two or three months
later which is how long it takes to put
a fucking comic out so it's like once it
goes in the world it gets supercharged
it seems to the point that he had his
character being tortured and given
essentially a flesh-eating disease and
then he got it in real life and nearly
died in the same situation you put his
character into so after that happened he
started writing his character just into
having audience and and then that's what
started happening in his life yeah you
gotta be careful with the shit man
because again as we were just saying the
closer you are to the source the closer
that shit comes to actually affecting
the fucking physics of your life thank
you for your art so we have for about 10
minutes left six six so we were talking
about darkness being you know a
sensitive to the darkness and then that
makes us inspires you to create beauty
in the world and promote it and meaning
and then we were talking about the hyper
sigil so can you speak maybe about that
process that you're doing right now in
the world
trying to make it a more beautiful place
well there's multiple ways of thinking
about that and looking at that
Jaakko will Inc elekid's that very
lovely another very lovely fashion with
his now that I've seen how dark it can
get I truly appreciate the lights in the
world I went through a period in my
heart cystic development have suddenly
been did that I don't want to know about
evil only want to know about love too
much darkness don't you sort of turn
away from the duck run away from the
duck get into dark but you can't do that
you have to go old all the way in and
then it's a case of trying to like
manifest that which you wish to exist
and developing the tools to be able to
do that and do as much as you can in
this little life in as useful and
effective fashion as possible and I'm
kind of trying to develop tools that can
transfer all these things to as many
people as possible you know and I'm
trying to do in such a fashion that it
works together and it doesn't confuse
people and you don't misconstrue things
which is why I'm try and give multiple
answers to that earlier question for
example because some things I'm going to
resonate with some people and some
people aren't I don't understand some
things and it's not necessarily until
you've seen the whole of the sphere that
you understand it's a sphere you know
you can go back to the place those cave
thing and oh there so yeah I'd sure like
a build a set of tools in the form of
records that can people can use in their
lives
in order to be more useful in the world
and thus have more meaningful and
beautiful lives and us that then
amplifiers out across the world you know
and just as a humble beet farmer that's
my little thing that I can do
so maybe this will be the last question
Aaron Rogerson you had a question about
here's previous comment about the the
sequels you can unmute yourself
uh yeah Kiera you mentioned you thought
the rise of shorten Peterson was the
first film in a trilogy where that's how
you perceived it
what would the second and third film be
called in the trilogy what would they be
called sure or I already want to
interpret it what happens in them
oh I got Peterson strikes back or
something yeah that would be a you'd
have a rise of the fetus in you'd have
then would you have fall and then
revenge to return of there's riddles
down to the negative words
and you want to sugarcoat it a bit I you
know obviously the next the album when
he returns is called resurrection and
the cover is like a fist like powering
through a fucking gravestone Infinity
Gauntlet with like a lay the fucking
giant energy beam coming out of it
type vibes thank you all ready for ya
you know the fucking vibes do you know
the vibes you've seen some movies is
shit see Glenn you had a question that
we can sneak another one yeah the most
meaningful slam Barnett oh my god uh I
forget you forget what you have you know
see oh sure
I've got the was then that neck one I
got the thing from leonard cohen's the
future which is very meaningful because
it's it's a kind of schedule from a
Leonard Cohen record this late this kind
of like chained but which is kind of in
reference to the holy dove and how that
that is never free but is also a
reference to I was making my first album
in New York at that point and it was
when I was going through that whole
journey of sign into a major record
label and being told I was going to be
do music to rap what the Beatles did and
all that smoke blowing up my ass while
simultaneously knowing having written
like a week before that happened not
written an article for a magazine about
how major labels were unnecessary in the
whole system was the devil and this that
and the other and then I recorded them a
in retrospect deliberately unreleasable
album with song titles called things
like thanks for all the AIDS and
what-have-you and it just reminds me I
was like full of so much love and
simultaneously like rage and I was this
little as this kid out there in the
world man and I'd manifested everything
I ever wanted and then deliberately
unconsciously simultaneously destroyed
the whole thing and it was the right
thing to do because it led me to be able
to do what I'm doing now and so yeah I
love that and also you know Leonard
Cohen's a bad motherfucker and he's
Canadian what is it with Canadians I've
got so many Canadians in my cultural
life we just we just gravitate to you my
friend I never been to Canadia yeah I
guess I never thought about it that much
but yeah and that's what I could kind of
I could talk about that for about three
hours probably and go into a deeply but
in the Cliff Notes version yeah that's
the vibes so time is up Kirra my friend
yeah
great grateful for you in your existence
you know happy to see you looking so
happy
meaning thank you that's very nice oh
yeah so I I have other things to tell
you about well email you but the link
what do i do their direction - oh if you
go do you need it how do I post it in
the chat yeah
let me find it therefore be what I just
switch to another tab at Daniel's Maxim
Berg his face and zoomed in massive like
unimpressed fashion that story of my
life Hey it was the shot over here
direct me somehow I found the chat oh
hey what I found you're gonna owe me oh
he's centered at first I think cool look
at the micro Syrians ill hair it's for
Sweden where's yeah you just could chat
in the zoom and you can pop it in there
and zoom is it down the boat ahead
alright Sheva alright alright alright
alright alright there we go okay
wonderful
thank you for having me yeah thanks for
being back yeah yeah I'd like to have
you on my team
what are these days if you'd like to
come a lot of love - all right boom I've
got a run over to the other side of the
room this is gonna be